Resume - Richard Jason December 20, 2020

Richard Jason

s.richard.jason@gmail.com

Software Engineer

linkedin.com/in/s-richard-jason in

+44 7378478743



"Life is about learning. To stop learning is to stop living"

A proactive software engineer who enjoy working in cross functional team as much as coding. I have a couple of experience in software development, including desktop, mobile and web app, both in startup and enterprise environment. I have been living in the UK for 3 years and am planning to continue working in the UK. I am pursuing chartered status within the British Computer Society (BCS).

Key Skills & Traits

Software Engineering

I am familiar with software solution lifecycle strategies, including requirement engineering, design, development, test, deployment, and production issue resolution. My most familiar technologies:

PHP Redux Backbone.jsHTML Python TypeScript Vue Fabric.js CSS SQL • C# Redis React Vuex D3.js Node.js MongoDb Java Git

Time Management

I continually improve this skill through risk and cost-benefit analysis which leads to prioritisation.

Collaboration & Communication

I regularly asks follow up questions, distribute information, and present progress to stakeholders, both technical and non-technical, while designing and implementing solutions.

Contagious Growth

Both my thirst for growth and analytical nature has been stimulating growth not only to myself but also to my surrounding.

Work Experience

JANUARY 2020 – DECEMBER 2020, WEYMOUTH, DORSET, UNITED KINGOM

Software Engineer (Full Time) - ASM Assembly Systems

Technologies: C#, JavaScript, D3.js, google charts, HTML, CSS, Lotus Domino/Notes, SQL, Power BI

As I continued to work in ASM after graduation, my responsibility grew. I:

- Reduced long and manual processes and duplications of efforts with applications I created, such as machine an integrated production planner and monitoring tool.
- Have been trusted to ensure the quality and deployment of the IT solutions I developed.
- Have been mentoring 2 placement students and enabled them to get started relatively quickly by taking maintainability and scalability seriously while working on my projects.
- Have been appreciated for contributing to solving non-technical challenges within organisation.

JULY 2018 – JULY 2019, WEYMOUTH, DORSET, UNITED KINGDOM

Software Engineer (Work Placement) - ASM Assembly Systems

Technologies: C#, JavaScript, google charts, HTML, CSS, Lotus Domino/Notes, Arduino, SQL

My role was to improve the manufacturing processes via software integration and provisioning. I:

- Enabled managers to gain data insight through user-friendly data collector and visualization tool, such as time logger application, reporting tool, production test etc.
- Reduced productions processes time with tool controller, such as screwdriver gun controller.
- Reduced weeks of time required to gather data down to seconds with a query tool I created by reverse engineering an existing 3rd party tool, while also ensuring data integrity.
- Has been appreciated for taking the lead in a couple of team projects.
- Has been appreciated for proactively contributing to an existing internal web app framework.

JULY 2016 – JULY 2017, BANDUNG, WEST JAVA, INDONESIA

Software Developer (full-time) - Ciptaloka.com

Technologies: JavaScript, Backbone.js, marionette.js, Framework7.js, fabric.js, HTML, SCSS, PHP, Phalcon, CakePHP, SQL, Bitbucket, Redis.

When I returned as a full time software developer after graduating, Ciptaloka decided to create mobile friendly website over native application for smart phone users. Within this experience, I:

- Worked in a semi Agile development environment using Kanban Board.
- Developed web application for mobile platform using MVC pattern.
- *Design Duel*: a simple user feedback tool where user are presented with 2 designs and they can vote for the one they preferred. This project gave me a glimpse into machine learning.

DECEMBER 2015 - MAY 2016, BANDUNG, WEST JAVA, INDONESIA

Mobile App Developer (internship) - Ciptaloka.com

Technologies: JavaScript, Backbone.js, Framework7.js, fabric.js, HTML, SCSS, PHP, Phalcon, SQL, Appcelerator Studio, Blue Stack

Ciptaloka was exploring their options to provide their service for smart phone users. As an intern, I:

- first learnt to develop a generic software product, where I would need to know who will be the potential user, what platform most of them use, and how they may use the application.
- developed mobile application version of ciptaloka.com using cross-platform development SDK.

Education

SEPTEMBER 2017 - SEPTEMBER 2019, WEYMOUTH, DORSET, UNITED KINGDOM

MSc Computing with Placement (Distinction)

Cardiff University

Technologies: Python, TensorFlow, Java, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Assembly, Hadoop, socket

My Dissertation was "Modelling Human Gaze Distribution on Various Kind of Images with a Relatively Simple Deep Learning Design". I combined various Neural Networks methodologies to predict the area of interest in a picture. Modules:

- Information Processing in Python (93)
- Distributed and Cloud Computing (81)
- OOP with Java (78)
- Web Application Development (78)
- Computational Systems (69)

- Software Engineering (65)
- Information Modelling & Database Systems (proactively sat in)
- Industrial Placement (70)
- Dissertation (88)

JULY 2012 – JUNE 2016, BANDUNG, WEST JAVA, INDONESIA

BSc Electrical Power Engineering (GPA 3.29/4.00)

Institute of Technology Bandung (ITB)

Technologies: MATLAB, VB, PHP, JavaScript, HTML, Git, Arduino, C/C++

I studied how to design, build, protect and maintain high voltage electrical network. I also took several modules related to Information Technology, such as Introduction to Information Technology and Digital & Microprocessor Systems. My thesis was about a Lighting Detection and Mapping System simulation, focusing on analysing and comparing the accuracy of the system with several configurations. I built the simulation software using VB.NET within Microsoft Visual Studio.

Certification

• ITIL 4 Foundation Certificate in IT Service Management

Organizations

2014 – 2015, BANDUNG, WEST JAVA, INDONESIA

Chief of Swimming Division

Swimming and Water Polo Club in ITB

As someone who used to be a swimming athlete, I joined the swimming and water polo club and was trusted to be the chief of swimming division. In this role, I:

- Created swimming, exercise programs, and managed schedules.
- Trained members of the division how to teach swimming.
- Observed all the club members' swimming skills progress.
- Started developing my leadership and communication skills.
- Learnt how to appreciate my work more, as I was eager to see my student's skills improve.

Projects

Lean Gress

Technologies Used: React Hooks, Redux, Gatsby, Firebase Auth, TypeScript, GraphQL, Apollo, Express, Mongoose, Mongo DB, AWS, Serverless Framework, Terraform, Bitbucket

Technologies Learnt: Dynamo DB, Vue, Vuex, Nuxt.js, Prisma

Outside working hours, I spend time working on my own side project for me to keep my hands on modern web technologies, such as react, redux, Gatsby, GraphQL, and etc. The vision of the project itself is to provide a simple and affordable SaaS which enable Collaboration and incorporate ERP tools, promoting visibility and collaboration that integrates well with the business processes and values. The first tools will be implemented includes organisation chart, project management, time logger, and production planner.

Hobbies and Interests

Sports

I swam competitively for 6 years and won a small city cup. I understand that the most important thing in competition is not just to beat our rivals, but to try to break our limit.

Technology

Hand-held and mobile technology plays a large role in my day to day life, so I constantly look for ways where I could improve their usage, to make both my own and other's lives easier and more efficient.

Systems Design and Analysis

Systems are a passion of mine; I enjoy taking part in discussions regarding systems and the analysis of them. I take great pride in being able to design and build a system that works quickly and effectively and then thinking of ways in which I can improve it further.

Development

Since young, I have always been obsessed with development, and feel upbeat and proud when I made an improvement, either to myself or my surrounding.